DARBY YULE

778-836-8719 • darby@theyulebrothers.com • darbyyule.com

PROFILE

I am a dedicated UX Designer with a robust background in user-centered design and a UI/UX Certificate from the University of Alberta. I create intuitive, visually appealing interfaces, align design strategies with business goals, and conduct comprehensive user research.

SKILLS

Design User Experience Design | Responsive Design | Content Management Systems | Information Architecture

Technical Usability Testing | Wireframing | Rapid Prototyping | Figma | Adobe Creative Suite | InDesign | HTML | CSS

Soft Skills Leadership | Communication | Collaboration | Critical Thinking | Creativity | Team Player

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer

Freelance | Burnaby, BC

May 2023 - Present

• Creating user centred designs and research for independent clients.

Developing Design Strategy, Design Systems, Logos and Information Architecture for small businesses.

· Clients include: Prince George Community Counselling Centre, Darkhorse Emergency, Peble.

Behaviour Support Worker

School District 44 | North Vancouver, BC

Nov 2020 - Present

• Observation and development of Functional Behaviour Assessments.

· Strategizing and developing plans to improve behaviour and success in the class for students with complex needs.

Musician/Songwriter

The Yule Brothers | North Vancouver, BC

Jan 2012 - Oct 2022

• Writing, recording and performing music/other artistic ventures.

• Entrepreneurial duties such as brand development, negotiating money, booking tours, social media management, content design, grant writing, managing technical contractors.

Youth Care Worker

School District 57 | Prince George, BC

Sept 2012 - Sept 2020

• Outreach and care for 15-30 students designated 'Severe Mental Health or Behaviour'.

· Crisis Intervention and mediation (suicide/threat prevention, substance abuse, grief and loss)

EDUCATION

UI | UX Certificate

University Of Alberta | Edmonton, AB | 2023

Community Access Certificate

College Of New Caledonia | Prince George, BC | 2012

PROJECTS

The Yule Brothers

Songwriter | Prince George, BC

Jan 2011 - Oct 2022

- Developed and lead a professionally touring musical act for over a decade.
- Career highlights include: releasing four studio albums, completing four Cross Canada Tours, premiering two singles on CBC Radio 2, 120k career Spotify streams.

Community Counselling Centre Website

UI UX Designer | Burnaby, BC

July 2023

- Complete redesign of the mobile and desktop website for the Prince George Community Counselling Centre.
- This included upscaling of UX Research, UI Design, Icon Design, Content Design, and Website Development.

Telus Optik: Then | Now

Producer | Prince George, BC Sept 2023

- Conceptualized and developed a six part documentary/performance about songwriters from the Northern British Columbia region. Songwriters told behind the scenes stories about their development as artists to an intimate audience.
- Duties performed included concept development, customer research, generative research, content design, media outreach, social media advertising, interpreting analytics, and graphic design.